Guide to the Rose Goldsen papers, [ca. 1950-1985]
Goldsen, Rose papers, [ca. 1950-1985]
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Rose Goldsen papers, [ca. 1950-1985]
14-25-1649
Rose Kohn Goldsen
79.3 cubic ft.
Research materials, writings, correspondence, administrative files, tape recordings, audio cassettes, video cassettes, and photographs
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Subject files containing research materials, writings, correspondence, and administrative files. There are also tape recordings, audio cassettes, and video cassettes of radio and television broadcasts, and photographs (primarily from Latin America). Subjects include public opinion, mass media, measurement of attitudes and values, economic development (Latin America), and social science methodology.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of Sociology, Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Subject files containing research materials, writings, correspondence, and administrative files. There are also tape recordings, audio cassettes, and video cassettes of radio and television broadcasts, and photographs (primarily from Latin America). Subjects include public opinion, mass media, measurement of attitudes and values, economic development (Latin America), and social science methodology.
Also, photocopy transcripts of 11 broadcasts on sociology over Ithaca, New York radio stations, February to May, 1974.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Goldsen, Rose Kohn.
Subjects:
Sociology--Study and teaching.; Sociology--Research.; Public opinion.; Mass media--Research.; Attitude (Psychology); Social sciences--Methodology.; Social sciences--Research.; Sociologists.; Women college teachers.
Places:
Latin America--Economic conditions--1945-
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I Personal and Office Records
Boxes 1 (1-27, 37-70)17 (1-29)43
Series II. Writings and Publications
Subseries A. Published Materials (1947-1984)
Boxes 2, 3 (1-30),6 (22-35)
Subseries B. Values Study (1949-1961)
Boxes 3 (31-52)
Subseries C. Radio Programs (1973-1984)
Boxes 4, 6 (10-21)
Subseries D. Lectures, Conferences, Hearings
Boxes 5, 6 (1-9)
Subseries E. The Show and Tell Machine
Boxes 6 (36-63), 7
Series III. Correspondence
Boxes 8, 9 (1-22)
Series IV. Teaching
Boxes 10-16
Series V. Author Files
Boxes 17 (37-55), 18-22
Series VI. Subject Files
Subseries A. Surveys and Commercials
Boxes 1 (28-36)
Subseries B. Funding Sources
Boxes 9 (23-63)
Subseries C. Extracurricular Activities
Boxes 17 (30-36)
Subseries D. Alphabetical Subject Files
Boxes 23-33
Subseries E. Conceptual Subject Files
Boxes 34
Subseries F. Miscellaneous Subject Files
Boxes 35-37
Series VII. Photographs
Boxes 38-41
Series VIII. Video Tapes and Films
Boxes 42
Series IX. Audio Tapes
Boxes
CONTAINER LIST
- Personal and Office Records
  - Rkg Life/Career Records
    - "Narrative Account of Career" 10/8/80 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Kohn family geneology (Box 1, Folder 1A)
    - Alice Cook, "Rose's Writing" - talk presented at reception for official opening of Rose K. Goldsen Papers, 4/20/92 (Box 1, Folder IB)
    - RKG curriculum vitae, career records, photo - 1953-61 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - RKG curriculum vitae, photo c. 1980-82 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - RKG profiles for biographical guides c. 1967-68 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Who's Who of Women 1980-81 (International Biographic Center) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Robin Williams' recommendations for RKG - promotions, grants 1976-81 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Legal records - divorce, name (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - "Rose's All-Purpoise Dolphins" (photos) (Box 1, Folder 7A)
      [RKG, Gail Bohrer, Alice Cook, Bob Love, Sally Wessels, Monserrat Zayas]
    - RKG's Will, Memorial Society records (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Memorial Service, Memorial Statements, Obituary 1985-86 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Douglas G. Webb, Letter to Matthew Lyons regarding RKG, 4/21/92; and "A Bibliography of Items Relating to Rose Goldsen.. ." 4/92 (Box 1, Folder 9A)
  - Financial
    - Life Insurance/TIAA/CREF (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1978 RKG deductible expenses (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Financial records 1979-80 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - First National Bank account (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Office
    - Goldsen Archives - Listing of Contents (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Cornell Media Services 11/80-4/81 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Copyright records and correspondence (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Copyrights - pending (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Book Orders (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Book to Order (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Publications received and paid 1977 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - RKG ' s assistant - notes, instructions (Box 1, Folder 2l)
    - Computer account, Computing Center, Coding (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Office - miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Home, Social
    - Longhouse Cooperative (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - 1981 Wood order, Woodstock Soapstone Company (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Hearthstone (woodstove) (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Posters, invitations (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Cornell Sociology Department
    - Christmas plays - Sociology Department, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Sociology Department - 1979-80 Annual Report (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Search Committee, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Sociology Department - 1980-81 Annual Report prep. (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Sociology Department, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Sociology Field Committee, 1982+ (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Assistant professor candidates, 11/82+ (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Undergraduate curriculum affairs, 1982-83 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Sociology - Coordinating Committee report 3/83; directory of Cornell sociologists, 1983-84 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Sociology Department, 1984+ (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Sociology Department candidates, c. 1984 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Sociology Department, 1984 - RKG schedule, course descriptions (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Winston Davis, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Barry Edmonston, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Arthur Fink, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Charles Hirschman, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Judith Long Laws, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Klimis Navridis, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Dorothy Welkin, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Alpha Kappa Delta - National Honorary Sociological Society (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Cornell University
    - Arts and Sciences (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Dave Burak (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - CURW Search Committee (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - General Education (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Graduate Admissions Procedures (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Knapp Committee; Corson/AAUP, 5/74 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Latin American Studies Program (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Statler Club - Board of Directors (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Statler, Fall 1984 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - University Faculty, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - University faculty - legislation (folder 1) (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - University faculty - legislation (folder 2) (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - University faculty - Faculty Council of Representatives (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Travel, Visiting Appointments, Foreign Contacts
    - Fulbright Award - application and correspondence, 9/56- 6/57 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Bordeaux visiting appointment, 1957-58 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Bordeaux visiting appointment - travel documents, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - RKG journal from Latin America trip, 9-10/62 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Santo Domingo trip, 6/8-10/65 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Santo Domingo trip, 6/11-14/65 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Santo Domingo trip, 6/15/65 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Santo Domingo trip, 6/16-17/65 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Santo Domingo trip, 6/18-21/65 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - OECD (France) Gassman, Salomon 1-7/80 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Sabbatic year 1981-82 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Colby College - Bill Cotter (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Cornell in Washington (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Institute for Policy Studies - including media course (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Spain - Menendez Pelayo International University (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - University of Barcelona (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Universidad Autonoma de Barcelona (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - University of California at San Diego (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - University of Kentucky (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - University of Ottawa (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Britain (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Cuba tour (sponsor: Union for Democratic Communications), 4-5/82; names and addresses (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Cuba trip - references, errands, correspondence (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - RKG notebooks from trip to Cuba, 4-5/82; + notes, photos (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Cuba, 4/30/82 - papers on mass media (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - John Spencer Nichols, "Functions of the Cuban Mass Media in Social Conflict," with note from Jose 5/24/82 (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - Cuba: articles (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Overseas contacts - unclassified (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Washington, DC notes, 3/84 (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - Card Catalog, Address
    - Card catalog of books, articles, reports, cassette video tapes, etc. owned by Rose Goldsen. (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Address files. (Box 43, Folder 2)
- Series II. Writings and Publications
  - Published Materials (1947-1984)
    - RKG Newspaper Articles - 1974-80 (in alphabetical order, by publication)
      - Access columns 6/4/79-10/20/80 (Box 2, Folder 1)
        ["Television Commercials and Involuntary Learning" 6/4/79; "Now That You've Seer the Picture, Why Not Watch the Book?" 10/8/79; "Time Compression: Speeding Up the Spiels" 10/20/80]
      - Daily News-Miner (Fairbanks, Alaska) columns - with correspondence 2/79-2/80 (Box 2, Folder 2)
        [TV and preschool play 2/17/7S media empires 2/24; Death in the West 3/3; "SM moves to mass media" 3/24; "Pseudo-events merit too much local news" 3/31; Three-Mile Island 4/21; "Can intelligent life survive at ABC?" 5/5; "New golden age of broadcasting.." 5/19; "TV education becomes Disney-ized 5/26; TV and computers 6/9; "Author Stone's book review bureaucracy" 6/16; "ABC buys lion's share of conglomerate" 9/29; "Belly buttons, bottoms, bosoms.." 10/13; "More ways to skin bank robbers" 11/3; "Fool your: senses with TV technology" 12/1; "Advertising looks at brain research" 1/19/80; "Lt. Columbo cracks the toilet paper case" 2/2]
      - In These Times columns - with Pat Aufderheide correspondence 7/30/79-3/12/80 (Box 2, Folder 3)
        ["We interrupt this commercial" 7/30/79; "Public interest is in the mind of the broadcaster, says FCC" 8/22; "See the movie, watch the book" 10/17; "Into the brain with ads" 1/30/80; "Columbo can tell the difference" 3/12; "Surely God approves" mailed 1/7/80]
      - Ithaca New Times - correspondence (Loretta Scott) and articles 1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
        ["Sex Manuals Revisited" 8/25; "Selling the Big Blue Marble" 9/8; "Embryo Sweepstakes - The No Win Situation" not published]
      - Ithaca New Times - Sept-Dec, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 5)
        ["The Powerful and the Powerless" 9/23; "Should Debates Use Public's Air?" 10/7; "Dr. Steel and Torpedo Fist" 10/14; "Gov't Winks While Toys Maim" 10/21; "The Trojan Story" 11/4; "Disenfranchised in the Voting Booth" 11/11; "Day Care Franchises" 11/24; "Monopolizing the TV Market" 12/9; "On the Bethe-Commoner Debate" 12/22]
      - Ithaca New Times - Jan-June, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 6)
        ["Family Hour: Constitutional?" 1/16; "TV: The Last Violent Straw" 2/: "'Roots' Impact Defused By Ads" 2/10; "TV Violence Backfires" 2/24; "'Network1 Reflects Reality" 3/3; "Hard Sell In Toyland" 3/10; "The Shogun Lesson" 3/24; "Opening the Mikes to retired Politicos" 3/31; "Cracker Jack Wrist Slaps" 4/7; "The Pitchmen and the Public Good" 4/14; "Ministry of Taste" 4/21; "Electronic Psych" 4/28; "A Plug-In Drug" 5/5; "TV's Angels Heralding Porn" 5/12; "Sneaky Smut Seeps In" 5/19; "A Grade School Lobby" 5/26; "All Items Sold Separately" 6/2; "Presence Fashion Dolls" 6/9; "Public Access Proposal" 6/16; "Free Market of Images" 6/23; "ACT, A Parents Lobby" 6/30]
      - Ithaca New Times - July-Dec, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 7)
        ["Pooh-Poohed Rights" 7/7; "A Raggedy Ann Blitz" 8/2; "Rerun Diplomacy" 8/9; "Naming Presidents" 8/30; "Soap' Bubbles Dirty" 9/27; "Images of Insanity" 10/4; "Watching Winking Dots" 10/11; "Watching Zamora Trial" 10/18; "Inside the Midway" 10/25; "Hustling My Image" 11/8; "My Last Talk Show" 11/15; "Class TV - No Thanks" 11/22; "Mind-Forming Power" 11/29; "Flight Out of Egypt" 12/6; "A Tip from Sweden" 12/13; "Thirty-Second Sex" 12/20; "Once Upon A Time" 12/27]
      - Ithaca New Times - Jan-May, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 8)
        ["Technically, Hype" 2/7?; "'Truth in Advertising" 2/7?; "Learning to Watch" 2/14; "Spaced Out Brain Waves" 2/21; "TV: The Brain Shredder" 2/28; "The Laws of Looking" 3/7; "FTC Drops a Bombshell" 3/14; "Celebrity Sweepstakes" 3/28; "Broadcasters Play God" 4/4; "Living Room Gambling" 4/18; "Holocaust: What Next?" 4/25 - incl. fan mail; "The Media Message" 5/9; "Non-Taxable Spectacle" 5/16; "The Born Innocent Case" 5/23]
      - Ithaca Times - June-Dec. 1978 ["Town Plan for Coy Glen: Give It a Try" 6/22; "Welfare for Television Broadcasters" 6/29; "AT&T Telephone Blitz" 7/6; "Minolta's Free-Fall Costly" 7/13; "Monsanto: A Young Blonde in Silver Gown" 7/20; "Schlitz Light: Drinking up Images" 7/27; "Too Many Peas" 8/3; "Argentina's Image, Elena's Reality" 8/10; "FCC Refuses Access" 8/24 "The Evening News: How to Retrieve It" 8/31; "Superman: SuperHype" 9/7; "Saturday Morning TV: More Wham, Bam" 9/14; "What's New in Prime Time" 9/21; "Performers Plug Their Own Wares" 9/28; "Lt. Colombo Cracks the Toilet Paper Case" 10/12; "The Osmond Empire: From Cattle to Clothes" 10/19; "Computer Controversy" 11/2; "Bill Cosby: Brand Loyalty" 11/9; "Surely God Approves" 11/23 "Northern Lights: TV Beams in Alaska" 12/7; "No Television: Cold Turkey Treatment" 12/14; "Jonestown Massacre: 'Event' of the Year" 12/21] (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Ithaca Times - Jan-Sept, 1979 [TV in the Nursery: The Take-over of the Imagination" 1/18; "Censorship in Marlboro Country" 1/25; "Mattel Takes Over Western" 2/1 "Corporate Press, Global Reach" 2/8; "Corporate School Text Packs: A Ton of Garbage" 2/15; "He-e-e-ere's Congress! Hollywood in the House" 3/1; S&M Chic Socks I to Women in Vogue" 3/22; "TV: Rhythmic Rhetoric Managin the News" 3/29; "Nuclear Crisis, Stock Market Bonanza" 4/5; "Expert Reveals: Just a Reactor Excursion" 4/12; "Sneak Preview: ABC's Prime-Time Lineup" 4/26; "Disneyland Goes to College" 5/10; "Mickey Mouse Regresses: Evolution in Reverse" 5/17; "TV & Computers: Can We Kick the Habits?" 5/31; "Corporate Bureaucracies The Principle of the Passed Buck" 6/28" "Do Broadcaster Violate Anti-Trust Laws?" 8/30; "The Public Interest: Once Again Up for Grabs" 9/13; "Now that You've Seen the Picture, Why Not Watch the Book?" 9/27] (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Newfield News and Grapevine columns 10/17/79-1/29/80 (Box 2, Folder 11)
        ["TV - nothing left for the imagination" NN 10/17/79; "The seduction of music" 10/24; "Your money or your life?" 11/7; "Computers to the rescue" 11/14; "The public interest - once again up for grabs" n.d.; "The Charms of Music" Gr 11/20; "How About Taking a Tip From Sweden?" 1/29/80]
    - RKG Short Writings - Miscellaneous 1973-81
      - Book reviews - with correspondence 1974-75 (Box 2, Folder 12)
        [Oh, What a Blow That Phantom Gave Me (Edmund Carpenter), Journal Communication Winter 1974; TV and the Public (Bower), Children and TV (Lesser), and The TV Establishment (Tuchman), Contemporary Sociology 5/75; seven books, "Reader's Report" Bookmark Series 4/75; Beyond the Stable State (Donald A. Schon), Administrative Science Quarterly 9/75]
      - Book reviews - with correspondence 1978-80 (Box 2, Folder 13)
        [The TinKazoo (Edwin Diamond), Contemporary Sociology 11/78; The Plug-In Drug (Marie Winn), American Journal of Sociology. winter 1977-8; 4 Arguments for the Elimination of Tv (Mander), Where the Law Ends (Stone), and Computer Power and Human Reason (Weizenbaum), Contemporary Sociology 1/80]
      - Short columns, letters to editor, with correspondence 1973-81 (Box 2, Folder 14)
        [Letter to Ithaca Journal re Cayuga Lake power station 5/17/73; Senate Sheet column; letter to Broadcasting Magazine re FTC 6/8/78; "Politics Conform to TV," Atlanta Journal/Constitution, 11/30/80; "TV is one-way "communication system" - for corporations," Media Report to Women 12/80; "The Economics of Never Never Land" - sent to NY Times Op-Ed Page, n.d.]
    - RKG Articles and Stories 1970-83 (in reverse chronological order)
      - Social impact article - notes 6/84 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - "Can Democracy Survive the New Communications Technologies?" - rough draft, notes c. 8/83 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - "Can Democracy Survive..." - Folder 2 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - "Foreword" to Love Canal: Science, Politics and People by Adeline Levine, 10/16/81 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - "Metaphor and Language as Clues to the Meaning of New Information Technologies" (statement for Pallman, Washington) 9/22/80 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - "The Great American Consciousness Machine: Engineering the Thought Environment," Journal of Social Reconstruction, April-June 1980 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - "The Great American Consciousness Machine" -Correspondence, Comments, Jan. -Aug., 1980 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - "Why TV Advertising is Deceptive and Unfair," Et Cetera Winter 1978 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - "Why TV Advertising is Deceptive and Unfair" -Publication Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - "Why TV Advertising is Deceptive and Unfair" -Circulation Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - "Why TV Advertising is Deceptive and Unfair" - Testimony at FTC and FCC Hearings, c. 2/79 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - "The View From Leticia," Cornell Review, Fall 1978 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - A Television Primer; I (A Little Goldsen Book) f 4/78 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - "Changing Channels: How TV Shapes American Minds," Human Behavior, Sept. 1977 - with correspondence, reprints (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - "Viro" and "Sister Tulia's Story," Praxis, Spring 1977 (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - Stories c. 1972-77 (Box 2, Folder 29A)
      - RKG interview in The Study of Society (2nd ed.) 1977 -with Dushkin Publishing correspondence (Box 2, Folder 30)
      - "Toys and the Imagination of Children," Human Behavior, December 1976 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - Playtime - Indoctrination Time (A Little Goldsen Book), August 1976 (Box 2, Folder 32)
      - Playtime - Indoctrination Time - master copy (typescript), 8/76 (Box 2, Folder 33)
      - Playtime - Indoctrination Time - corrected master, 9/76 (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - Playtime - Indoctrination Time - publicity, copyright (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - RKG and Azriel Bibliowicz, "Plaza Sesamo: 'Neutral1 Language or ' Cultural Assault '?, " Journal of Communications, Spring 1976 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - "Assembly-Line Violence, Picture Tube Guns," Cornell Journal of Social Relations, Spring 1976 (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - "Assembly-Line Violence..." - correspondence and distribution (Box 2, Folder 38)
      - "Children Must Be Raised by Hand," Human Behavior, April 1976; reprinted Women's Day mid-Oct. 1976 with correspondence, fan mail (Box 2, Folder 39)
      - "Literacy Without Books: The Case of Sesame Street," in Educational Television, ed. Robert Amove, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 40)
      - "Throwaway Husbands, Wives and Lovers," Human Behavior, December 1975 - with correspondence, newspaper response (Box 2, Folder 41)
      - "On the Trail of the Elusive Datum" typescript 7/7/75 (Box 2, Folder 42)
      - "Television's Mode of Address," Journal of Communications, Sprina 1975; requests for copies; copyright correspondence (Box 2, Folder 43)
      - RKG and Azriel Bibliowicz, "Un Programa de T.V.: 'Plaza Sesamo," Eco, Feb. 1975 (Box 2, Folder 44)
      - RKG and Azriel Bibliowicz, "Mindlessness in Plaza Sesamo," International Broadcast Institute Annual Meeting, Sept. 1974 (Box 2, Folder 45)
        [RKG and AB, "Insensatez en Plaza Sesamo"]
      - "Naming and Signalling," 6/6/74 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - "Science in Wonderland," Society, Mav/June 1973 - with correspondence (Box 2, Folder 47)
        [Irving Louis Horowitz, Leo Lowenthal, Willard Gaylin, etc.]
      - "Relational Systems, Genetics and Images of Man," typescript, 12/13/72 (Box 2, Folder 48)
      - "Naming the Game is the Name of the Game I.," Seminar o Political Relations Between Latin America and the US, Lima, Peru, 11/27/72 (Box 2, Folder 49)
      - "Naming the Game is the Name of the Game: Further Comments by the Author," 12/9/72 (Box 2, Folder 50)
      - "Nombrar el Juego es el Nombre del Juego," Lima Conference, 12/1/72 (Box 2, Folder 51)
      - "Stories," typescript, March 1972 (Box 2, Folder 52)
      - "A.J. Liebling, Honey, the Press Sure Misses You," typescript, February 1972 (Box 2, Folder 53)
      - "NBC's Make-Believe Research on TV Violence," transaction, October 1971; replies by J. Ronald Milavsky and Allen H. Burton; reply by RKG; NEC study progress report (Box 2, Folder 54)
      - "NBC's Make-Believe Research..." - correspondence, newspaper coverage 5/71-2/72 (Box 2, Folder 55)
        [Coffin, Milavsky; Irving Louis Horowitz, Mary Symons Strong, Sarah Flynn (transaction); Allen Barton (Bureau of Applied Social Research); Burns W. Roper; Les Brown (Variety), Walter Sullivan (NY Times)]
      - "NBC's Make-Believe Research..." - Paul Lazarsfeld correspondence 5/71-2/72 (Box 2, Folder 56)
      - "NBC's Make-Believe Research..." - related correspondence 5-8/71 (Box 2, Folder 57)
        [Herbert Schiller; Phillips Davidson (Public Opinion Quarterly); Betsy Cohen (FTC); Don Cahalan, Sidney Hollander, Jr. (American Associatic for Public Opinion Research) ]
      - "Why Do They Call It Media Research?," typescript, October 1971 (Box 2, Folder 58)
      - Review: Donald A. Schon, Beyond the Stable State, 197] (Box 2, Folder 59)
      - "Clearing the Air, or How Fares the First Amendment - ] It Alive and Well?," Glad Day Press, Ithaca, 1971 - anc Media Ithaca correspondence (Box 2, Folder 60)
      - "The Structure and Function of the Mass Media Viewed as a Sociological Institution," typescript, 1971; "La Estructura y Funcion de los Medios de Comunicacion Masiva Vistos Como Institucion Sociolocrica, " Razon y Fabula, Bogota, Colombia, February 1970 (Box 2, Folder 61)
      - "Antecedentes de un Programa Centrado en los Medios de Comunicacion Masiva en Colombia," typescript, 9/16/70 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Publication Inquiries 1977-1984
      - Notes for columns (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Inquiries - try these magazines (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Inquiries - Feb, 1977-Feb, 1979 [WSKG TV/Radio 2/77; "How About Taking a Tip From Sweden?" 12/77; Contemporary Sociology review essay c. 1978; C. Wright Mills volume 11/78; The Humanist 12/78; NYU Education Quarterly 12/78-1/79; Contemporary Sociology reviews 1978-9; Cornell Alumni News 1/79; McCall's 1-2/79) (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - National Public Radio - Keith Talbot, Katherine Ferguso - Jan-Sept, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Parents Choice correspondence 6-10/78 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Human Behavior - "TV Advertising and Involuntary Learning," March 1979 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Inquiries - March, 1979-Oct, 1982 [Journal of Communication] 3/79; New York Times Arts & Leisure/Op-Ed 9-10/79; Columbia Journalism Review 1-2/80; Channels -Les Brown, 6/79; Society, review of Harvey Levin, Fact and Fancy in TV Regulation 7/80; access article - Sally Steenland letter 8/80; "Old-Boys Network Alive and Well (Cornell Eleven case) 2/81; Journal of Community Communications - low power TV 5/81; Society Boddie vs. ABC-Geraldo Rivera 6/82; New Internationalist 9-10/82 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - In These Times - Pat Aufderheide, 10/9/80 (Box 3, Folder 8)